Guide to the Isaac Rabinowitz papers, [ca. 1965-1988]
Rabinowitz, Issac papers
- Series XII. Bound Manuscripts from Rabinowitz collection #4661
  - [Midrash on Megilat Ester], 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 28; 10 leaves, bound and cased; 19 cm.
    Notes: Ms., written in a North African Sephardi hand. Judeo-Arabic text; very fragmentary and stained. Title on cover of ms. and on spine of case: Midrash on Ester.
  - Yad ḥaruzim, 17--; 4661 Bd. Ms. 29; 68 leaves; 25 cm.
    Notes: Ms., written in an Italian hand. The rhyming phrases are drawn mainly from the Talmud. This ms. is not the same as the Yad ḥaruzim of Gershom ben Moses Hefez, which was printed in Venice in 1700. The ms. vol. also contains 2 loose inserts: 1. A prayer for utterance by a person in jail and awaiting trial; 2. An anecdote about a Jewish trapeze-artist who saved a family in Alençon from death by fire.